Guide to the Records of the Washington Square Association, Inc. MC.94
New York University Archives
Records of the Washington Square Association, Inc.
1908-1996
1955-1965
New York University Archives
Washington Square Association
MC.94
13.75 Linear Feet in 45 boxes
The Records of the Washington Square Association demonstrate the organization's strong commitment to civic organizing. The Association organized community events and addressed zoning, traffic, and housing issues. These efforts brought the Association into close contact with numerous municipal agencies such as the Department of Transportation, the Parks and Police Department, the Board of Estimate, New York University, Community Planning Board #2 and a number of historic preservation organizations. Overall, the Association's records reflect the history of a changing urban neighborhood.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of membership directory information, which is restricted for 70 years from date of creation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In April 1988, following a legal agreement between New York University and the Washington Square Association, New York University acquired 18 linear feet of records generated by the Washington Square Association, Inc. (Accession 88-014). Contacts for the Association were its president, Anne-Marie Sumner and its executive secretary, Jean B. Krampner. In March of 1992, approximately 1.5 linear feet of additional documents were incorporated into the existing collection. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 06.004, 07.021, 88.015, 94.015.
Arrangement
The Records of the Washington Square Association are arranged chronologically in eight series5:
I. Administrative Publications
II. Administrative Minutes
III. Financial Records
IV. Membership Information
V. Administrative Correspondence
VI. Association Activities
VII. Annual and Special Events
VIII. Photographs and Drawings
Historical Note
In December of 1906, a dozen householders of the Washington Square area between 14th Street and Washington Square Park were invited to the West 10th Street home of Cornelius Berrien Mitchell, where he proposed the formation of an association in order "to maintain the present desirable character of the neighborhood." The "character" of Washington Square had been established at the Square's initial development in the 1830s as the "American Ward (Ninth ward), a liberal model of cleanliness, good citizenship, and self-respect." In the 1870s, in response to the influx of a large population of Irish to the east and to the west of the Square, as well as a sizable African-American settlement nearby, the old-line patricians politically allied themselves with the Tammany machine. By the next decade the Irish and African-Americans had been pushed out of Greenwich Village, not by right-wing efforts but by a new wave of Italian immigrants. Along with the influence of changing population trends, other psychological factors contributed toward the propensity of the long-standing residents for conservatism; the Square had lost its preeminence as the most fashionable address in New York City. By the 1890s, the "Old Row" houses on Washington Square North looked outdated as "the leaders of fashion had moved uptown, abandoning the lower (Fifth) Avenue to...a few old families [which] hung on" and shops, apartments, and hotels.
The genteel atmosphere around the brick and marble townhouses was threatened by commercial incursions. New and imposing loft buildings filled with immigrant workers appeared, accompanied by the numerous pushcarts which served the adjacent tenement population. Articles emerged in the press concerning the disturbing increase of tramps and immigrants loitering in the park. The long-time residents felt beleaguered on many fronts. A neighborhood association that would act as liaison between the residents, the city authorities and private companies was established in a novel attempt to restrict the noise, pollution, and bustle of mercantilism. The founders of the Association felt that their mission, which they touted as public-spirited, was doubly patriotic: first, as an enterprise which involved individuals in the process of civic participation; and second, as championing preservation of the "old" Washington Square neighborhood. An early test of the system occurred in 1909, when the municipal government took up the role of unwanted developer in an attempt to build a courthouse in the venerable Washington Square Park and was successfully repulsed by the Association.
In response to complaints by the Washington Square Association and millions of other beleaguered Manhattanites against uncontrolled real estate development, the city administration appointed a Zoning Commission (1914) to determine present and future land use. The Association effectively petitioned that a large part of their district remain residential. The fruits of the Washington Square Association's victory can still be seen today on the side streets off Fifth Avenue which retain more residences below 14th Street than above it. The early Board and Members of the Association were long-time residents of the area and many were from old, influential families (such as the Delanos, Rhinelanders, Wanamakers, Van Rensselaers, Schermerhorns, even that of the Mayor of New York, George B. McClelland). Their demand of an aesthetic for their community, as well as their political clout, is evident in initial plans which permitted sidewalk cafes and established tree-planting programs.
This combination of cold politics and warm neighborliness characterize the Association through seven decades of community service. Several Greenwich Village traditions have been established over the years, such as the Washington Square Christmas Celebration, which was initiated in 1924 by the Association in cooperation with the Department of Parks, and featured a tree-lighting ceremony and a carol sing-a-long. In 1920 the Association funded and erected the Memorial Flagpole in Washington Square Park, dedicated to the local heroes of World War I. All civic problems, from trash collection to police protection, contribute to the quality of life on the Square and repeatedly appear on the Association's agenda. A programmatic sampling, by decade, can serve to show the varied, far-ranging projects undertaken by the Washington Square Association. In 1932 Depression-era artists are given an outdoor gallery around the park through the efforts of Mrs. Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney. The Outdoor Art Exhibit continues to the present as a semi-annual event. In 1949 the "Save Washington Square Committee" is formed and protests the destruction of south Washington Square for the New York University's Law Center. In 1958, although the attempt to preserve the Rhinelander Houses (northwest corner of the Square) fails, the developers modify the new apartment building constructed there to conform with the design of the remaining historic row houses, and community awareness grows toward support of landmark preservation legislation. In 1963, almost a century after Boss Tweed opened a roadway through Washington Square Park, the Association finally forces the city to close the Park to all vehicle traffic. In 1976 the Association is fundamental in organizing the U.S. Bicentennial festivities for Washington Square. The Washington Square Association was the first neighborhood organization of its kind in New York City and has served since its inception as a paradigm for many other community alliances.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Washington Square Association are strong in the area of community involvement in such issues as zoning, housing, traffic, parks, and public festivities. The records reveal a positive working relationship between the Association and other metropolitan institutions including the Board of Estimate, New York University, Community Planning Board #2, historic preservation organizations, and the municipal Departments of Transportation, Parks, and Police. The issues that the Washington Square Association has tackled represent the changing concerns and values of one urban neighborhood over a 75-year time span. Historically, its failed campaigns are no less important than its numerous victories. Overall, these documents provide rich resources for the study of urban history.
Six linear feet of records which offered no evidentiary or informational values were eliminated (multiple copies, non-related publications, etc.). Most of the paper is in good condition, but some files (mostly prior to circa 1950) contain very brittle materials which should be carefully handled. Gaps appear in all series, most notably in the annual publications (for example: Yearbooks/Annual Reports exist in the collection only from 1920, 1934-37, and 1950; Art Exhibit Catalogs exist in the collection only from 1947, 1951-52, 1955-58, 1967). In March of 1992, approximately 1.5 linear feet of additional documents were incorporated into the existing collection. In order to maintain the original sequence with a minimum of alteration, the incorporation of the second accession in one case necessitated a box designation of 6a (see Container List) as a supplement to the administrative minutes that constitute this series subdivision.
Photographs.; Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Minutes (administrative records); Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Annual reports.; Washington Square (New York, N.Y.); New York Public Library. Jefferson Market Library; Community Planning Board No. 2
- Series I: Administrative Publications
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - By-Laws, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Histories, Rosters, and Biographies of Officers, 1912-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hehmeyer, Alexander, President biography, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DeRham, Henry L., President biography, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tafel, Edgar, President biography, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Informational Booklet, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Informational Booklet, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Informational Booklet, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Informational Booklet, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yearbooks, bound, 1908-1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yearbook, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yearbook, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yearbook, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yearbook, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Yearbook, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Yearbook, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Yearbook, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yearbook, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Yearbook, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Yearbook, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Yearbook, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Yearbook, 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Yearbook, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Yearbook, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Yearbook, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting: Notices, Report, Objectives, 1919-1921 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meeting, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meeting, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meeting, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Notices of Annual Meetings, 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Annual Meeting, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meeting, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Annual Meeting, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Annual Meeting, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Annual Meeting, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Annual Meeting, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Annual Meeting, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Annual Meeting, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Annual Meeting, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Annual Meeting, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Annual Meeting, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Annual Meeting, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Annual Meeting, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Annual Meeting, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Annual Meeting, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Annual Meeting, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meetings, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meeting, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meeting, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meetings, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Annual Meeting, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meeting, 1985 (Box 4a, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting, 1986 (Box 4a, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meetings, 1987-1989 (Box 4a, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meetings, 1990-1999 (Box 4a, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meetings, 2000- (Box 4a, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1951-52 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins and Drafts, 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, 1948-1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bulletins, 1955-1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bulletins [Bound Copy], 1907-1915
- Series II. Administrative Minutes
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1946-1950 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Secretary's Notebook, 1966, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Secretary's Notebook
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1954-1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors: Mailing Lists, 1971-1979 (Box 6a, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1970-1979 (Box 6a, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1981-1985 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1986-1989 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1990-1995 (Box 6a, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1996-1999 (Box 6a, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 2000- (Box 6a, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors: External Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 6b, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 6b, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1953 (Box 6b, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1954 (Box 6b, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1955 (Box 6b, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1956 (Box 6b, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 6b, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 6b, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box 6b, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 6b, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors: Internal Correspondence, 1990-2002 (Box 6b, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors: Miscellaneous (e.g. News Clippings), 1966-1967 (Box 6b, Folder 12)
- Series III. Financial Records
  - Treasurer's Report, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1950-51 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bequest: Eliza Lawton, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bequest: Victoria Gambarelli, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bequest: Weinberg, 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Estates: Weinberg, 1977-1979, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Financial: Account and Record (Book), 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Financial: Account and Record (2 Books), 1965-1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Financial: Accounts Payable, 1965-1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Financial correspondence, invoices, statement and receipts, annual reports, tax records and other miscellaneous records., 1954-2003 (Box 8a, Folder 1-10)
  - Financial Records: Internal Revenue Service, 1960-2003 (Box 8b, Folder 1-4)
  - Financial: Bank Statements, 1970-2003 (Box 8c, Folder 1-7)
  - Cash Accounts, 1912-1916
  - Cash Accounts, 1917-1920
  - Cash Accounts, 1921
  - Cash Accounts, 1923
  - Cash Accounts, 1926-1928
  - Cash Accounts, 1932-1937
  - Inserts from Cash Accounts Book 1932-1937 [Financial Statements], 1939-1943
  - Checkbook, 1909-1910
  - Checkbook, 1916-1917
  - Checkbook, 1917-1918
  - Checkbook, 1918-1920
  - Checkbook, 1920
  - Checkbook, 1922-1925
  - Checkbook, 1923-1924
  - Checkbook, 1927-1928
  - Checkbook, 1927-1928
  - Checkbook, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Checkbook, 1934-1937 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Membership Payments, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Special Accounts and Advertising, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Fund Subscriptions, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Membership Payments, 1927 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Membership Payments, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Christmas Donations, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Membership Payments, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Membership Payments, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Financial Records (Box 30)
- Series IV: Membership Information
  - Miscellaneous (regarding WWI, ordinances, membership cards, and dues), 1913, 1920-1923 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence regarding membership, 1938-1941 (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - Membership Lists, 1941-1967, 1974-1975, 1990, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 5-20)
  - Membership-Contributors Lists, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Contributors Lists and Correspondence, 1988-2001 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Membership Correspondence, 1947-1959 (Box 10, Folder 1-11)
  - Membership Correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
  - Complaints, 1949-1954 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Miscellaneous Membership Correspondence, 1967-1975 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  - Bills for Membership Dues (A-F), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Bills for Membership Dues (G-Z), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Invitations to Renew or Join, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Membership Correspondence, 1970-2002 (Box 11a, Folder 1-6)
  - Resignations and Deaths, 1958-1965, 1989 (Box 11a, Folder 8-9)
  - Certificates of Membership - blank, circa 1960s (Box 11a, Folder 10)
  - Membership Lists, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Membership Lists, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Membership Lists, 1927 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Membership Lists, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Application for Membership Cards, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Application for Membership Cards, 1927 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Application for Membership Cards, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Application for Membership Cards, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Application for Membership Cards, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Application for Membership Cards, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Membership and Banquet Records (Box 31)
- Series V: Administrative Correspondence
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Business Correspondence, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Press Release Information, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Activities
  - City Planning Commission, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - City Planning Commission, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - City Planning Commission, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - City Planning Commission, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - City Planning Commission, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Zoning, 1949-50 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Zoning, 1951-52 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Zoning, 1953-54 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Zoning, 1955-1956 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Zoning, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Zoning (Jan. - Apr.), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Zoning (May - Dec.), 1960 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - City Zoning Proposal, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Zoning, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Zoning, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Zoning, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Zoning, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Zoning, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Membership, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Community Planning Board #2: By-Laws, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Jan. - Mar.), 1966 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Apr. - Jun.), 1966 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Sept. - Nov.), 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Dec.), 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Rules, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Nominating Committee, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Jan.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Feb.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Mar.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (May), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Jun.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Sept.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Nov.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Dec.), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (Jan.- Mar.), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Minutes (May - Nov.), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Monthly Reports, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Community Planning Board #2: Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 15, Folder 19)